Pushkar Kumar Mishra Linux/AWS/NOC Engineer

3 +years of experience as Linux Systems Administrator and NOC Engineer with good work experience in Amazon Web Services especially on S3, EC2, Ami, snapshot, Cloud Watch.

Strong perseverance and diligence towards attaining challenging goals and possess good communication skills and quick learning ability.

Skills_

RHEL6, RHEL7, Centos, Ubuntu

AWS,Docker,GIT,SVN

jenkins

Kinesis

SOL

Work History

Quytech may 2019 till the date.

Code-brew labs. (System engineer (devops) Jan 2019 to march 2019 date

Value First Digital Pvt Ltd. NOC Eng. (AWS /Linux) Feb 2018 to Jan 2019 date.

Atharv Trade Exim Pvt. Ltd System Admin (Linux)

Jan 2017 to Jan 2018

Work Experience

Quytech (system Engineer (aws)

- Responsible for architecting, designing, implementing and supporting cloud based infrastructure and its solutions.
- Hands-on knowledge of software containerization platforms like Docker and container orchestration tools like Kubernetes and Docker Swarm
- Proficient in AWS services like VPC, EC2, S3, ELB, AutoScalingGroups (ASG), EBS, RDS, IAM, Cloud Formation, Route 53, CloudWatch, and CloudFront.
- Unix/Linux systems administrator with experience configuring, monitoring, upgrading and maintaining systems hardware, software and related infrastructure.
- Experienced in creating multiple VPC's and public, private subnets as per requirement and distributed them as groups into various availability zones of the VPC.
- Used security groups, network ACL's, internet gateways and route tables to ensure a secure zone for organization in AWS public cloud.

- Created and configured elastic load balancers and auto scaling groups to distribute the traffic and to have a cost efficient, fault tolerant and highly available environment.
- Possess good knowledge in creating and launching EC2 instances using AMI's of Linux, Ubuntu, RHEL,

System Engineer (AWS /Devops)

Core-brew labs (aws/Devops)

Roles & Responsibilities:

Project name bharatpe-

- Responsible for architecting, designing, implementing and supporting cloud based infrastructure and its solutions.
- Rectified many issues by instituting best practices in system log analysis, backups, network operating center security, user account/permissions management and systems/ software auditing.
- Automated AWS components like EC2 instances, Security groups, ELB, RDS, IAM through AWS Cloud information templates.
- Linux Administration, includes the provisioning and maintenance of Linux servers in production and development environments.
- Used IAM for creating roles, users, and groups and also implemented to provide additional security to the AWS account and its resources.
- Implemented domain name service (DNS) through route 53 to have highly available and scalable applications.
- Maintained the monitoring and alerting of production and corporate servers using Cloud Watch service.
- Snapshots to take backups of the volumes and also images to store launch configurations of the EC2 instances.
- Servers Monitor on Nagios Monitoring tool

NOC Engineer (AWS /Devops)

Value First Digital Pvt Ltd.

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Servers Monitor on Nagios Monitoring tool
- MySQL Backup creation and restoration
- LAMP installation on AWS EC2 Instance
- LVM Management
- Restart the apache service
- Generate a Ticket & Assign a ticket to particular teams.
- Manage the load of Server on a critical stage.
- Space Release on Servers
- Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones
- Cloud Watch Installation and Configuration For Monitoring
- Hands on create a Simple Storage Service (S3)bucket creation and upload the data on S3
- Creating/Managing Snapshots/Volumes
- Create AWS Instances

Linux L1 Support Engineer

Atharv Tradex Exim Pvt. Ltd. - July 2017 to Jan 2018

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Installation and configuration of apache Linux database install like mongo dB and SQI.
- Unix/Linux systems administrator with experience configuring, monitoring, upgrading and maintaining systems hardware, software and related infrastructure.
- Schedule a job through crontab
- User Management User creation and add to secondary group of user
- Give a File & Directory permission
- Nagios Monitoring of Server

- Installation of RHEL7.2
- NFS Server Installation & Configuration
- MySQL Backup creation and restoration
- Disk space checking

process checking through TOP command

Education

:

2014 MCA Passed with 66% in 2012-2014 Ignou Delhi.

2012 **BCA Passed with 63% in 2009-2012 Ignou Delhi.**

2008 12th Passed With 66% In 2006-2008 Bihar Intermediate Board, Patna

2005 **10th Passed with 50% 2004-2005 Bihar intermediate Board, patna**

PERSONAL DETAILS:

<u>Contact</u> number : 8700136759, 8237504599

Name : Pushkar Kumar Mishra

Date of Birth : 5th jan1991

Nationality : Indian

Address : Laxmi Garden, Gurgaon Haryana

Languages

Known : English, Hindi.

Note- I am ready to join immediately.